Christopher Bowman

Software Engineer - New London, CT | 508-302-9166

cbowman.se@gmail.com | Github | Portfolio | LinkedIn

SUMMARY

Software engineer specializing in full stack JavaScript technologies. Worked on multiple teams to develop full stack applications. Prior to software development I have experience in mechanical engineering. Dedicated to leveraging my unique background and knowledge in software development to ensure the delivery of quality products.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages - JavaScript | Python | SQL | Mongo | JSON | EJS | HTML5 | CSS Libraries, Frameworks and Databases - React.js | Express.js | Django | Flask | AWS | PostgreSQL | MongoDB

PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

Internship - DevOps Engineer | 6/2023 - Present SpaceLab

AWS | Linux | Rest API | GraphQL | Docker

- Responsible for setting up landing pages with AWS EC2 instances.
- Worked on a team of 2 software engineers to manage AWS accounts.
- Researched best subdomain and API deployment methods.

Independent Consultant - Software Engineer | 3/2023 - Present

Scott's Landscaping, Inc

Express | React.js | Node.js | HTML | CSS | JSON

- Enhanced user experience and user interface (UX/UI) design decisions, resulting in 30% increase in website engagement and 20% decrease in bounce rate.
- Developed responsive web applications, improving website accessibility across devices and increased user retention rate by 15%.
- Successfully managed the transfer of domain registrar, email provider transfer, and updated DNS records.

General Dynamics Electric Boat - Structural Engineer II | 6/2020 - 11/2022

- Produced FEA models for 2 Virginia and 1 Columbia class Submarine, using ABAQUS scripting (Python).
- Analyzed with Finite Element Method software ABAQUS/CAE and a Python based house code.
- Collaborated with engineers to produce well-organized and professional documentation for calculations.

University of Massachusetts, Amherst - Teaching Assistant | 1/2019 - 12/2019

- Supported two engineering classes gaining leadership experience.
- Hosted 2 and 3-hour, well attended, office hour sessions twice weekly for 14 weeks and accurately graded over 300
 projects of high technical difficulty.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

Money Mania - 3/2023

MongoDB | Express | React.js | Node.js | HTML | CSS | JSON

- Money Mania is a MERN application designed for students to learn about finance for the GA 2023 Gamifying Hackathon and placing runner up.
- Worked on a team of 3 UX/UI designers and 4 software engineers.
- Responsible for the backend server as well as 3 client pages.

Millie's Messenger - 2/2023

Sockets.IO | MongoDB | Express | React.js | Node.js | HTML | CSS | JSON | JWT

- Millie's Messenger is a MERN chat application designed to live chat with other users using Socket.IO.
- A user can login and send private messages to others, join a live chat room, and set a status.

HAPI HOUR - 12/2022

React.js | JavaScript | HTML | CSS | Grid | Flexbox | thecocktaildb.com

- HAPI Hour is a front-end web application built to help users navigate recipes from thecocktaildb API.
- Users can search by name/ phrase search engine, search by ingredient search engine, or start with a base ingredient choice and browse.

EDUCATION

• Full stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive, twelve-week, 450+ hour program.

University of Massachusetts, Amherst - Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering | 5/2020

• 3.44 GPA